<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="_c74_vig.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<vignette name="Oneirotomy: Workarounds" package="Oneirotomy">
  <metadatalist>
    <metadata name="author">Tim Georg Heinze</metadata>
    <metadata name="tag">Xenorama</metadata>
  </metadatalist>

  <h1>Oneirotomy: Workarounds</h1>

	<h2>Whimsical objects in the GL-world</h2>
  <p>
    Certain objects are designed to serve an immediate function when working in the GL-domain, and they do so amazingly! However, when attemping to work with them <i>offline</i>, they may not work as expected, if at all. The following paragraphs may help in implementing this package's objects in such a way that these objects' functionality can be leveraged nonetheless.
  </p>

  <h2><o>jit.anim.path</o></h2>
  <p>
    <o>jit.anim.path</o> only outputs its transformation data to target GL-objects when both a local <b>render context</b> is <i>enabled</i> and that very target object is directly attached to it. The data it outputs is a case for <o>the.cerebellum</o>, however, the latter needs to be implemented additionally and <i>@active 4</i> to record the data output by the <o>jit.anim.path</o> but not output in parallel, but to output during rendering instead of the latter, which will yield no data when the render engine is not enabled. Furthermore, <o>the.jit.thalamus</o> needs to be set to <i>@toggleworld 0</i> so that all world data is collected along with signals and timing data. <br/>
    Consider also to set <o>the.cerebellum</o> to <i>solo 1</i> if complex signal processing is occuring during recording. This way, data can be collected separately.
  </p>

  <h2><o>jit.mo.func</o></h2>
  <p>
    Every active <o>jit.mo.func</o> object will require a <o>the.jit.mojo</o> object attached to its inlet in order for the <at>speed</at> attribute to be controlled by the progressing frames rather than internally. Disabling <o>jit.world</o> will not produce the desired timing in these objects otherwise.
  </p>
  <br/>
  Previous: <b><link type="vignette" module="Oneirotomy" name="oneirotomy-03_known-limitations">Known Limitations</link></b>
  <br/><br/>
  Next: <b><link type="vignette" module="Oneirotomy" name="oneirotomy-05_development">Development</link></b>
  <cr/>

  <seealsolist>
		<!-- <seealso name="timing_events_topic" module="topics" type="vignette" />	-->
    <seealso name="the.jit.thalamus" />
  </seealsolist>

</vignette>
